<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WorkoutApp</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_reset">Start Program Over</string>
    <string name="action_progress">Workout Progress</string>
    <string name="action_program">About Program</string>
    <string name="title_activity_progress">Progress</string>
    <string name="return_button_text">RETURN</string>
    <string name="close_day_button_text">CLOSE OUT DAY</string>
    <string name="close_cycle_button_text">CYCLE FINISHED</string>
    <string name="check_success">Checkmark your successes</string>
    <string name="return_day_button_text">RETURN TO DAY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_welcome">Program Info</string>
    <string name="rest_timer_title">REST TIMER</string>
    <string name="stop">STOP</string>
    <string name="time_rem_msg">Time Remaining: </string>
    <string name="setup">Enter Starting Weights</string>
    <string name="title_activity_setup">Setup</string>
    <string name="action_lifts">About Lifts</string>
    <string name="grats">Congratulations!</string>
    <string name="day_done">You made it!</string>
    <string name="get_rest">Don\'t forget to rest up!</string>
    <string name="exercise">Exercise:</string>
    <string name="set">This Set: </string>
    <string name="day">Day: "</string>
    <string name="weight">Weight: </string>
    <string name="reps">Lift Reps: </string>
    <string name="welcome"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">You\'ve taken a great step towards the new you. On this page, we\'ll offer an explanation
     of how this program works. Then we\'ll setup your starting weights, and explain how to determine those. There\'s
     quite a bit of information here, but don\'t worry. The app will handle all of the calculations and tracking for you.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="rep_cycle"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">This program is based on the principle that adding 1 rep is approximately equivalent to
     adding 10% to your working weight. So through the course of each cycle, you\'ll increase your reps by 1 each week (
    from 8 to 12). Then after 5 weeks, we\'ll reset back to 8 reps and repeat. </p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="day_cycle"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">Resting between workouts is just as important as the exercises themselves. Therefore, we
     recommend you try to allow for 8 hours of sleep per day. In that spirit, we also step down the intensity of each
     day\'s workout throughout the 3-day week. On Day 1, you\'ll use 100\%% of your working weight. On Day 2, you\'ll drop
     down to 90\%%. On Day 3, 80\%%. Since all 6 exercises are essentially "full-body" lifts, it\'s important to follow
     this method so that your body has enough rest to continually increase load week after week.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="cycle_prog"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">On Day 1 of your 5th week of each cycle, you\'ll note whether you were successful in all 12
     reps of each particular exercise WITH PROPER FORM. If you were, then the app will add 10% weight for your next cycle.
     For any individual exercises that you weren\'t successful at that weight, don\'t worry. You\'ll just stay at that same
     weight for the next cycle. We bet that you\'ll be successful next time.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="star_separator">******</string>
    <string name="safety">IMPORTANT: DON\'T SACRIFICE PROPER FORM FOR THE SAKE OF WEIGHT OR REPS!</string>
    <string name="lifts"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">The 6 primary exercises you\'ll be doing are the Squat, Bench Press, Row, Shoulder Press, Stiff-
    Legged Deadlift, and the Curl. You\'re probably noticing that you don\'t see any abdominal exercises here. That\'s
     because since these lifts are all full-body exercises, you\'ll already be building up your core strength. After cycle 2,
     if you feel you want to add abdominal exercises to your routine, we suggest you do so on off-days. But give yourself
     a couple of cycles first so your bones and supporting tissues can get used to carrying the barbell and weights. Whenever
     possible, these exercises should be performed using a barbell. Isolation machines simply don\'t provide the same kind
     of bone density and supporting tissue growth that the barbell offers. </p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="alt_intro">Acceptable alternative approaches:</string>
    <string name="row_alt"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">Rows can be done with either barbell or dumbells, depending on availability</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="shoulder_press_alt"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">Shoulder Presses should be done standing, if possible. And can be done with either barbell
     dumbells. If standing is not an option (for instance, if you\'re using a Smith machine), then seated Presses are fine.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="stiff_alt"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">If Stiff-Legged Deadlifts are too difficult to perform correctly, you can bend at the knees to
     make it more comfortable. You will still get the same back and hamstring workout either way.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="curl_alt"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">Curls can be done with dumbells if you prefer, or a curling bar. If you are using dumbells, just
     make sure to come to a complete stop between each rep, so that you are not "swinging" the dumbells.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="warmups"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">For the first 3 exercises each day (Squat, Bench, Row), you\'ll do 2 warmup sets prior to your
     2 working sets. Each of the remaining exercises will require only 2 sets at working weight. Your first warmup set will be
     at 25\%% of your working weight and the second warmup set will be at 50\%%. If either of these is less than a bare barbell,
     then just use the barbell (Olympic barbell is 45lbs).</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="determine_wt"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">You will use your 10 rep max for each exercise. To determine your 10 rep maxes, go to the gym
        one day (at least 2 days BEFORE starting the routine), and perform one set of each exercise until failure (as many reps
        as you can do with good form). Try and pick a weight that will bring you to failure at around 10 reps (for a more accurate
        calculation). Take note of the weight you used and how many reps took you to failure and then plug them in to this
        calculator linked below. This will give you your 10 rep max (your weights cycle 1)</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="rep_calc">The 10-rep calculator link is </string>
    <string name="missed_day"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">If you can only get to the gym 2 days in a particular week, don\'t worry. Just do 100% weight for
     both of those days.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="disclaimer"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">You should consult a physician before embarking on any weight-lifting program. As well, if you
     experience PAIN during lifting, STOP immediately and consult your physician. This is a lifestyle, not a marathon. Stay safe!</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="to_menu"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">We recommend you open the exercise instruction page from the menu at the top right of the screen to
     familiarize yourself with the details of each exercise. Also, at any time during the program, if you need to reset your
     lifting data, you can do so from the same menu.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="welcome_next"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">Are you ready to begin? Just click SETUP and we\'ll setup your starting weights after you
     determine your 10-rep max, as mentioned above.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lifts_info">Lifts Info</string>
    <string name="lift_info">Information about Lifts</string>
    <string name="lift_welcome"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify">On this page we will provide some information that will briefly describe each of the exercises you
     will be performing during this program. We suggest that if you are unfamiliar with these lifts, please research proper
         form beyond what is included in this short message. If any exercise is difficult to perform or causes pain, please
        consult a physician and adjust accordingly.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="squat_title">Squat</string>
    <string name="bench_title">Bench Press</string>
    <string name="row_title">Row</string>
    <string name="overpress_title">Shoulder Press</string>
    <string name="deadlift_title">Stiff-Legged Deadlift</string>
    <string name="curl_title">Curl</string>
    <string name="bench_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> Lay flat on bench with hands about 12 inches wider than shoulders. Pinch shoulder
         blades together, as if you were trying to hold a quarter between them. With feet flat on the floor, arch your
         back upwards slightly. Lower the bar in line across the middle of your chest. If it helps your lift,
         you can allow the bar to gently bounce off of your chest.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="squat_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> Hold bar across shoulders, behind your head, with hands much wider than shoulder
     width apart.Pinch shoulder blades together, as if you were trying to hold a quarter between them. Do
     not allow your hands to roll back, which will make your hands/wrists/arms support the bar. The bar should be supported
     solely by your back. Feet should be slightly wider than shoulder width, and your feet should be angled in the
     direction that your knees will be travelling, as to avoid undo lateral pressure on your knees. Keep your chin and
     chest up. It helps if you remain looking at a point on the ceiling across the room. Push backwards with your
     butt and then bend your knees, which will allow the bar to lower until your thighs are parallel with the floor.
        Make certain to keep your feet flat with the weight on your heels. Your knees should NEVER travel beyond
         the middle of your feet. Keep your back as flat as possible. Imagine a straight line being drawn from
         your head, down your back, and off your butt. It can also help to have a friend watch you to help you
         from not allowing your butt to curl down and up again when transitioning from
         down to up position.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="row_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> Hold the bar with hands shoulderwidth apart.Keep your shoulders up and back.
        Bend your knees slightly, and lean your back forward at about a 45 degree angle.Pull the bar upwards
         toward the area between your chest and your abdomen for each rep.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="overpress_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> While standing, support the bar across your chest just below shoulder height.
    Hands should be a bit wider than shoulder width apart, and legs should be spread about the same.While pushing
         the bar upwards, keep your back straight and your chest up. Move your head back to allow the bar to travel
         upwards, rather than moving the bar around your head.When you reach the top of the lift, continue a bit
         higher by shrugging your shoulders up.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="deadlift_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> While bending and lifting with your knees, bring the bar up from the floor to a
     standing position.Hold the bar with feet and hands about shoulder width apart.While keeping
     your shoulders up and back straight, push back with your butt while allowing the bar to travel down a straight line
     towards the floor.It is important to keep your back straight and your shoulders up so you do not hurt your back.
    At the bottom of the motion, you should feel your hamstrings stretch. Initiate the upward return by pushing your hips
     forward as you return your back to an upright position.At the top of the motion, arch your back and push
         your chest out.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="curl_info"><![CDATA[
    <html><body><p style="text-align:justify"> While bending and lifting with your knees, bring the bar up from the floor to a
     standing position.Hands and feet should be shoulderwidth apart or narrower.With your arms hanging
     straight down, begin the curling motion.Keep your elbows in a fixed position at your side during the lift.
        At the top of the curl, squeeze your forearm and biceps together.</p></body></html>]]></string>
    <string name="title_activity_day_done">Day Finished</string>
    <string name="title_activity_timer">Rest Timer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lift_cycle">Successful Lifts</string>
    <string name="explain_success">(lifts that you were successful completing all 12 reps at 100% on Day 1 with proper form)</string>
    <string name="title_activity_secret">Admin</string>
    <string name="title_activity_reconcile">Reconcile</string>
    <string name="action_reconcile">Reconcile Weights</string>
    <string name="reconcile_message">You can adjust your weights here.</string>
    <string name="action_theme">Color Theme</string>
    <string name="blue_theme">Blue Theme</string>
    <string name="red_theme">Red Theme</string>
    <string name="mixed_theme">Mixed Theme</string>
    <string name="select">SELECT</string>
    <string name="title_activity_theme">Color Theme</string>

</resources>
